
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>AI and Deep learning Blog</title>
      <link>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog</link>
      <description>A blog created to provide information about state of the art Deep learning and AI methods</description>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>dr.krishangovind@gmail.com (Kishan Govind)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>dr.krishangovind@gmail.com (Kishan Govind)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://mlwithkishan.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      
  <item>
    <guid>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/LLM-model-from-scratch</guid>
    <title>Comprehensive Guide to Building Large Language Models from Scratch: Key Considerations and Technical Insights</title>
    <link>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/LLM-model-from-scratch</link>
    <description>Building a large language model (LLM) from scratch involves significant financial and computational resources, requiring extensive data curation, model architecture design, and scalable training processes. This blog explores the complexities and costs of developing LLMs, including key steps like data sourcing, quality filtering, model design choices, and training techniques. While creating an LLM can offer tailored solutions for specific needs, the investment is often substantial. Alternatives like prompt engineering or fine-tuning existing models are more practical for most use cases, providing similar benefits without the high costs of building a model from scratch.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>dr.krishangovind@gmail.com (Kishan Govind)</author>
    <category>Large Language Models</category><category>AI</category><category>Machine Learning</category><category>LLM</category><category>Transformers</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/medical-blog-ranking-llama2</guid>
    <title>Predicting accuracy of medical blogs on colon cancer using Llama2</title>
    <link>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/medical-blog-ranking-llama2</link>
    <description>In the digital age, many blogs provide information on diseases, early signs and symptoms, and treatment methods. However, the accuracy of this information can vary. AI, like Llama2, can be used to analyze these blogs and predict the correctness of the information. By training Llama2 on verified medical data, it can cross-check the information in the blogs, identifying inaccuracies and ensuring the content is reliable. This helps users access accurate health information and make informed decisions.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>dr.krishangovind@gmail.com (Kishan Govind)</author>
    <category>llama2</category><category>colon cancer</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/construction-material-quantity-takeoff-Part1</guid>
    <title>Introduction to Construction Material Quantity Takeoff:- Counting the symbols</title>
    <link>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/construction-material-quantity-takeoff-Part1</link>
    <description>Counting items in a construction plan is an important task where we count the items present in the drawings. In this blog, we introduce the problem statement and the challenges in developing a AI based model which can be used to count the items.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>dr.krishangovind@gmail.com (Kishan Govind)</author>
    <category>Construction</category><category>Quantity Takeoff</category><category>Yolo</category><category>Object Detection</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/construction-material-quantity-takeoff-Part2</guid>
    <title>Construction Material Quantity Takeoff Using AI:- Counting the symbols</title>
    <link>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/construction-material-quantity-takeoff-Part2</link>
    <description>A two step AI based solution is proposed to count symbols in a plan for material quantity takeoff in construction. The first step is to perform object detection where the objective is to predict all the symbols present in the drawing. Once we have all the symbols, then we can perform indexing of symbols from the legend using dinoV2 model and Faiss vectordatabase.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>dr.krishangovind@gmail.com (Kishan Govind)</author>
    <category>Construction</category><category>Quantity Takeoff</category><category>Yolo</category><category>Object Detection</category><category>dinoV2</category><category>Faiss</category><category>vectordatabase</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/dreambooth-dislocations-synthetic-images</guid>
    <title>Generate synthetic images of dislocation microstructure using Dreambooth</title>
    <link>https://mlwithkishan.com/blog/dreambooth-dislocations-synthetic-images</link>
    <description>Finetuning dreambooth provides a unique way to generate synthetic images using just a couple of images. DreamBooth is a technique for personalizing text-to-image models such as Stable Diffusion by fine-tuning them with a small number of images (usually 3 to 5) of a specific subject. This method allows the model to generate images that incorporate the characteristics of the subject in new, synthesized scenes.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>dr.krishangovind@gmail.com (Kishan Govind)</author>
    <category>dreambooth</category><category>stable diffusion</category><category>dislocation</category><category>synthetic data</category>
  </item>

    </channel>
  </rss>
